[Episode 2]
The Wu and Yao Clans fell,
while humans and dragons rose.
Such was the Primordial Era.
The six ancient races fought endlessly.
Humans won and ruled the world.
Hongjun preached the Way;
Three Pure Ones parted.
Ling'e,
you...
Ling'e?
Li Changshou, wake up your junior!
You put her to sleep,
so you're responsible.
You wretched disciple!
Who called me?
Mentor, real combat?
Is it real combat now?
Real combat?
Eat one bite at a time.
Time to eat?
Nonsense.
Eat what?
Read one book at a time.
What are you writing?
Yes, yes, yes.
Why write all that down?
That's what I was thinking.
As a small branch
of the Pureheaven Sect,
shouldn't we know this history?
Yes.
Sect disciples are divided
into four stages,
which are the Refining Stage,
the Ascension Stage, the Reversion Stage,
and the Reunion Stage.
Each stage has nine phases.
Each phase is fraught with perils.
Perils.
Talent, will, and fortune
are all essential.
Mentor,
what comes after the Reunion Stage?
After that, one may face
the Tribulation.
If they survive,
they'll become immortals.
This is further divided
into Primal Immortal, Verity Immortal,
Celestial Immortal, and Aureate Immortal.
In all of Ascendance Sect,
few have reached
such a realm.
Patience, patience.
Just have a little patience.
Alright.
When you can at last
ignite this mid-level talisman,
you'll have truly started.
Wait, I...
I didn't...
I didn't hear you say anything.
How did it just ignite?
I felt that the talisman
was calling for me.
Then, in an instant, a warm current
slipped through my fingers.
A prodigy!
Our division has a prodigy!
Ancestral masters above!
A prodigy!
Time to offer incense!
Mentor is too easily pleased.
So, I'm a formal disciple now?
Offering incense won't help.
Better let me
teach you practical combat.
Senior?
Where did you come from?
I've been here all along.
Right beneath this earth vein.
Earth...
What a marvelous spell!
Do you still recall the answer
from that day?
I do.
Pretend I didn't see it.
And go find you.
Yes.
Then, if you're in danger
and need to escape,
what do you rely on to come find me?
My own wits.
Wrong.
Now, I'll teach you the second lesson.
The art I just used:
the Evasion Art.
If you need to escape to find me,
you'll rely on this art.
I'll only show you once.
Watch closely.
When the heaven and earth intertwine,
transformation arises.
Senior!
With this art,
you can travel freely underground.
Nothing can stand in your way.
Senior, that's amazing!
If you meet a mighty foe,
use it at once and find me.
Understand?
Yes, Senior.
Isn't this Mentor's flute?
I sneaked into his quarters
and took it as a teaching aid.
Return it for me.
All right.
What I showed you just now
is called Earth Evasion.
One of Five-Element Evasions.
Master all five within three years.
This scripture
is profound and boundless.
Recite day and night, learn by heart.
The Scripture of Steadiness?
But I've never heard of it.
Who wrote this, Senior?
Look at my face. Who do you think?
Then it must be you, Senior.
[Scripture of Steadiness]
All my experience is in it.
Concise yet profound, deep yet simple.
Blending classics and history,
serious and witty.
Dwell in peace, yet think of danger.
Think of misfortune.
Act with steadiness.
Reject entanglement with karma.
May I ask a question?
Sure.
Senior,
has your handwriting
always been this bad?
Copy it one hundred times.
Due by tomorrow morning.
No!
[Jade Division]
My fish!
What are you doing, Ling'e?
You're not training hard enough.
No, it wasn't me, Mentor.
It was not me.
Always up to mischief.
My fish!
♪An unexpected meeting
in this Primordial World♪
Here, Mentor.
♪This lad, at first, is hard to admire♪
♪In a flash, I recall our near misses♪
♪Fearing inescapable karmic threads♪
♪Someone has unsettled your heart♪
♪An edge hides, yet flows with ease♪
♪Making me lean down and confirm slowly♪
♪Not knowing what love truly is♪
♪Just as it was at first♪
♪Day after day, with whom to share♪
♪Never walked the road
of joy and sorrow♪
♪No better than a mortal♪
♪Not knowing love's depth♪
♪Who truly cares♪
♪How to walk this different path
with you♪
♪At storm's end, stars gleam,
and clouds drift♪
♪Together we smile,
watching moonrise and sunset♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[3 years later]
Senior,
lately,
I've been training the Invisibility Art,
no appetite for food or tea,
devoting myself entirely.
Enough, enough. Stop talking.
Show me already.
Go now.
Wait for me.
Senior,
can you see me now?
Guess: Am I over here,
or over here?
Junior.
You can't see me now, can you?
Junior, where are you? Junior!
You cannot see me.
Truly impressive.
Junior.
I can't find the way back.
Where are you?
Guess where I am.
- Where am I?
- Junior.
Are you here, Junior?
I am not here.
Junior.
I am over here.
How could you see me?
You are invisible, huh?
I did turn invisible.
You practiced for so long, huh?
You must be
making fun of me!
You even made me come here.
[Hall of Mortal Coils]
[Jiu Wu, 5th disciple
of Griefbane Division]
[Elder of Ascendance Sect,
Warden of Hall of Mortal Coils]
I focused on this side of the board,
yet I missed
the mess on the other side.
With one careless move,
the whole game is lost.
Uncle,
your weiqi skills are superb.
I won by pure luck.
Enough.
Well.
I accept the loss.
What do you want this time?
Uncle,
here's the thing.
In a few days,
we'll have our once-every-thirty-years
Trial Assembly, right?
Yes.
You serve
as Warden of the Hall
and oversee the event.
It must be hard on you.
Right, right.
That's right.
You are absolutely right.
Don't beat around the bush.
Just say it.
Then I shall be direct.
I'd like
to take a look
at the Spirit Treasure Map.
The Spirit Treasure...
Why do you want to see that?
You know me, Uncle.
My cultivation's too low.
I can't compete for treasures.
I just want
to feast my eyes on it.
That will be quite enough.
I see.
You have no real skills,
so you want to cheat,
get some good Spirit Treasures,
and then run away, right?
You lost, Uncle.
Rest assured.
I always
keep my word.
You want to see it, right?
Come, get ready.
Hold on, let me get ready.
Come on.
I'm ready.
Here.
Three, two...
Well?
I accepted my loss.
Would you?
Uncle, you leave nothing to chance.
No wonder you're the Warden.
I shall take my leave.
Do come again next time!
I refuse to believe
I can't beat you just once.
Sure.
Goodbye.
This game...
[Steady, Certain Victory]
Senior,
with one glance,
you'd know
where the Skyscraping Vine is?
Of course not.
But, you see,
I have this.
It's called the Soul-Capturing Pearl.
It has a powerful function.
It records everything the wearer
sees before their eyes.
I'm ready.
This is called image recording.
Watch closely.
It is truly miraculous!
That is nothing yet.
There's something even more amazing.
It can even pause at will.
Could this be the Image Recording Art?
It's beyond the Image Recording Art.
It is called the Montage Art.
What an astonishing art!
Let us search
for the precious Skyscraping Vine.
[Mass Grave, Cattle Land]
Miasma Grove.
Kuru Land.
[Skyscraping Vine]
Here it is.
Mission accomplished!
Copy the Scripture
of Steadiness 300 times.
Uncle Jiu Wu must've seen
you move that weiqi piece.
He just didn't expose it.
You broke Article 16, Rule 6
of the Humanity Oath.
No.
That only calls for 250 copies.
Then what about the extra 50?
What are those for?
We agreed beforehand:
I cause the trouble;
you take the blame.
Fine.
I will copy it.
But Senior,
why do you need the Skyscraping Vine?
Find the realm ruling all living beings.
The Celestial Court.
Li Changshou,
do you like
the Great Tribulation?
Senior, say something.
Can you guarantee you get assigned
to Miasma Grove?
I am not telling you.
[Ascendance Sect, spirit testing
for the Trial Assembly]
[Ascension Stage, Refining Stage,
Reversion Stage, Reunion Stage]
These three:
Refining Stage VII, Ascension Stage III,
and Reversion Stage II.
We request the Elders' judgment.
[Trial Grouping]
[Kuru Land, Miasma Grove]
The destinations have been decided
[Jambu Land, Jingwei Island]
according to your cultivation.
[Cattle Land, Mass Grave]
They are
Mass Grave, Western Land,
Firecloud Grotto, North Land,
and Jingwei Island, South Land.
Excellent.
Such progress since last time.
I'm so proud of you.
Come, let us drink to it!
Next one, come up.
Come.
Zhang Henan, Mistveil Division.
Chen Ziting, Spiritkin Division.
Why isn't Senior here yet?
[Griefbane Division,
Elder Evaluation Site]
This move is a bit off.
[Jiang Jingshan, Sect Elder,
Lord of Skyrend Division]
Everyone is acting like fools.
In this freezing cold,
why climb so high?
Senior Qi.
Old friend.
Long time no see.
Still as mischievous as ever.
You're old, indeed,
but no longer my friend.
I heard of your two disciples:
one eloquent and persuasive,
the other improving by leaps.
You are truly blessed.
Kuai Si.
Let me tell you.
Ling'e joining my division
follows the sect's rules.
You can't go back on your word.
What are you saying?
I'm happy for you.
For this trial,
you must pick good places
for your two dear disciples.
What do you mean?
Did I say you could leave?
What?
Lan Ling'e, Jade Division:
Reversion Stage I.
Ling'e's improved remarkably.
Jingwei Island seems fitting.
What do you all think?
No objections.
Neither do I.
Senior Qi, you have no objections?
Ling'e, good for you.
You've grown a lot.
The elders assigned you
to Jingwei Island.
Though it is dangerous,
[Jambu Land, Jingwei Island]
I believe you can handle it.
You'll be fine.
Thank you, Aunt.
Go now.
Senior, you're finally here.
How did it go?
Not so great.
Jingwei Island is great.
Why say not so great?
But I didn't get
the Miasma Grove you wanted.
Miasma Grove is dangerous.
You can't go with me.
But, Senior,
the Innate Treasure tests cultivation;
then the elders assign by results.
How can you be sure
you'll end up in Kuru Land?
Well, about that,
I have a plan.
Who is this?
Which division is she from?
I have never seen her before.
Who is she?
Hey, Pretty.
No, no.
Junior.
Are you a new disciple?
You're not joining Aunt Jiang Jingshan,
are you?
She's the Lord of Skyrend Division,
Warden of the Discipline Hall.
She's rumored to be hot-tempered
and scornful.
Her disciple, Youqin Xuanya,
is known as our top immortal candidate.
Though I haven't seen her,
she probably takes after her mentor.
She must be fierce-looking too.
How knowledgeable of you, Senior.
Calling me Senior feels so distant.
[Wang Qi, Spiritkin Division]
I'm Wang Qi of Spiritkin Division.
May I ask your name?
[Youqin Xuanya]
I'm Youqin Xuanya
[Skyrend Division]
of Skyrend Division.
[Sixth Princess of the Donglin Kingdom]
Nice to meet you.
Xuanya.
Senior Yuan Qing, long time no see.
Long time no see.
Skyrend, Youqin Xuanya.
Mistveil, Yuan Qing.
Come up.
Senior, you're putting on an act.
A beauty like a flower.
You don't even...
Others see only her appearance.
But what I see
is karma.
Here comes Xuanya.
That's Yuan Qing
of Mistveil Division, right?
Both so young,
already at Reversion Stage V!
Impressive!
Senior Jiang, Junior Kuai,
what are your plans?
Xuanya mentioned
she wants to gather herbs
in Miasma Grove.
Though it's no safe place,
it's good training for her.
They're childhood sweethearts.
Naturally, Yuan Qing
wants to go with her.
Understood.
But these two
are this generation's best,
plus Liu Yan'er of Gravecap
and Wang Qi of Spiritkin.
If all these talents
are going to Miasma Grove,
that seems a bit wasteful.
Why not
split them up a bit?
No need to split them up.
Yuan Qing goes to Kuru Land.
Kuai Si,
what an arrogant
and autocratic manner.
Warden Jiang is quite blunt.
I'll send my disciple with yours.
Why not accept this goodwill?
I watched Yuan Qing
and Xuanya grow up.
As for young people's hearts,
no need to guess.
No need to guess.
I understand.
Very well.
Let Yuan Qing
have his wish.
If it leads to a match,
that would be a fine thing.
However,
in that case,
this team's strength
would be much better.
We should add
a slightly weaker disciple.
Weaker?
Xuanya, Yuan Qing,
look after each other in Kuru Land.
You rascal.
Satisfied now?
[Kuru Land, Miasma Grove]
Thank you, Aunt.
Go, go, go.
Let's go, Xuanya.
Jade Division, Li Changshou.
Your turn, Senior.
Coming.
Everyone,
what cultivation level
would suit this disciple?
Ascension Stage IX?
♪I dare to live my own way♪
♪In the Primordial World♪
[Reversion Stage]
[Reunion Stage]
[Ascension Stage]
♪The stars smile at fireflies♪
[Stage VIII]
[Stage IX]
Not bad, Changshou.
Since when are you so capable?
If Changshou goes to Miasma Grove,
he won't know what hit him.
Well.
Isn't that a bit wasteful?
Then,
Refining Stage IX?
[Ascension Stage]
[Refining Stage]
How'd you regress?
That's also wasteful.
Changshou's trying to kill me!
♪Let the thoughts weigh♪
[Stage VIII, Stage IX]
♪Unruly♪
♪A carefree smile♪
Forget it.
Why not Refining Stage IV?
Refining Stage IV?
That's Miasma Grove!
He'll be too weak.
It's fine.
Yuan Qing's there.
He'll protect him.
You're just worried
that if the others are too strong,
they'll steal your disciple's treasures.
Let's keep looking.
Ascension Stage fits better.
Then,
Ascension Stage I?
[Refining Stage]
[Ascension Stage]
No, no.
I think
Refining Stage is better.
But then the gap isn't wide enough.
Ascension Stage III?
Refining Stage is better.
Refining Stage.
Stop arguing. Refining Stage II it is.
Safety first for this trial.
Refining Stage III is better.
Ascension Stage IV.
Ascension Stage III.
[Refining Stage, Ascension Stage,
Reversion Stage]
[Stage IX, Stage VIII, Stage I]
No, Ascension Stage II.
What's going on?
Release all your Qi, quickly.
Stop dawdling!
Yes.
It's settled, then.
Pick a disciple at Ascension Stage II.
[Ascension Stage]
[Stage II]
You rascal.
You really haven't improved.
Just playing it steady.
And you're proud of it?
Li Changshou, Jade Division.
Ascension Stage II.
He walks right into it.
It seems heaven wills it.
Let Li Changshou, Jade Division,
join the Miasma Grove team.
Senior, rest assured.
He's Yuan Qing's peer.
I'll ask Yuan Qing
to look after him closely.
[Kuru Land, Miasma Grove]
Aunt,
do I really have to go
to Miasma Grove?
Stop shaking first.
I'll put in a good word.
Don't be scared.
All right.
Don't be afraid.
Since the result is decided,
changing it arbitrarily
would be unfair to others.
What do you mean?
Heaven's will cannot be defied.
I'll go
to Miasma Grove.
Changshou...
I'm leading this trial.
Destination: Miasma Grove.
Five members per team.
We have: First in the last trial,
[Liu Yan'er, Gravecap Division]
Youqin Xuanya, Skyrend.
Second, Yuan Qing, Mistveil.
17th, Wang Qi, Spiritkin.
44th, Liu Yan'er, Gravecap.
And finally,
Li Changshou, Jade.
The 2,222nd.
You really are something.
If it weren't for you,
Junior.
- Here, sorry.
- You ranked last in the trial.
Stop that.
I can't enter the exam hall.
I can't keep you safe.
This isn't some market.
Even your mentor
didn't come out unscathed.
My mentor went there too?
Ask him if you want to know.
Anyway, good luck to you all.
Junior Changshou.
This...
Your hair is so soft.
Not bad.
Rest easy, Junior Changshou.
We're destined to be teammates.
I'll keep you safe.
Xuanya, don't you worry.
No matter the dangers,
I'll find
the Fire-Repelling Herb for you.
This is my own cultivation.
Senior Yuan Qing, don't worry.
Exactly.
Mind yourself, Yuan Qing.
Junior, don't be afraid.
My mentor mentioned Miasma Grove.
Though it is perilous,
it's not as scary as Aunt Jiu says.
In comparison,
if you meet the Dragon Clan
in the East Sea,
that would be truly dangerous.
Dragon?
Let me tell you,
the Dragon Clan in East Sea
relies on their former sea dominance
and stirs up trouble,
bringing calamity to all.
With our Ascendance Sect around,
they wouldn't dare act out.
But if they ever get a pretext,
humans and dragons
will inevitably clash.
The Dragon Clan in East Sea.
What are you muttering about?
Listen to me carefully.
If you face a foe you can't beat,
just run.
You must survive at all costs.
Survival comes first.
Especially you, Changshou.
What's wrong with your cultivation?
Your talent is clearly decent.
This shouldn't be.
Just steady.
Aunt,
our division's secret art
is best at reading Qi refiners' states.
More precise than a Spirit Diagram.
Test him with it, quickly.
Hurry, hurry!
No, no, no.
No, no.
Why are you shouting?
- Quick!
- No, Aunt.
I'll come clean.
The reason
my cultivation stayed the same
is that I
was too impatient.
I wanted a shortcut.
So,
I tried all kinds of pills.
Not only did it not improve,
but also...
It also...
I contracted a condition:
Touching a woman makes me convulse.
You just said
you convulse when you touch a woman?
I've never heard of that.
Is that a real condition?
Yes, yes, there is.
There really is.
Aunt,
since Changshou can't touch women,
I'll do it, then.
- Quick.
- Senior.
Senior Yuan Qing, you doubt me?
I...
Why won't you believe me?
Fine, I...
I'll prove it to you.
You forced my hand.
Changshou,
he never said he didn't believe you.
Is it true or not?
- Not on me!
- Girls, don't touch Changshou.
Are you all right?
That boy, keep Changshou safe.
Let's find a place to stay first.
Changshou!
[Anshui Tavern, Donglin Kingdom]
Senior, careful! Careful!
Rest a moment, Senior.
Today, I lost composure
before Aunt and fellow disciples
and delayed our journey.
I'm utterly ashamed.
I had intended
to take this secret to my grave.
Forget it, stay away from him.
Stay away, don't touch him.
Don't touch him.
It's all my fault.
I'll drink three cups
as self-punishment.
Senior, I prepared some Miasma Talismans
and Detoxification Pills for you.
I hope they can help.
If you don't accept them,
I cannot be at ease.
No need.
I appreciate the thought.
This perilous cultivation
is to temper body and mind.
If I rely on external aids,
it would put the cart before the horse.
Thanks for your guidance.
Senior,
though your cultivation is lower,
your will is strong and resilient.
You will surely achieve greatness.
The path ahead is long.
Do not lose heart.
Let us encourage each other.
Sure.
[Yuwen Ling, General of Donglin Kingdom]
Yuan Qing.
Come here quickly.
I'm Yuwen Ling.
Greetings, Young Master Yuan Qing.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Rise.
Anshui City is part of Donglin Kingdom.
And Xuanya's mortal identity
is the Sixth Princess
of Donglin Kingdom.
How do you know so clearly?
I'm the fourth son
of the Senior Grandee.
I've known her since childhood.
No wonder you're always after her.
So, you're childhood sweethearts.
I have affection,
but she has none.
I didn't call them here.
We're seeking immortality.
You idlers shouldn't meddle.
Even if Her Highness forbids it,
I won't stand idly by.
These ten are our elite.
Each is a match for ten thousand.
What did you just say?
I didn't catch that.
Truly impressive.
I alone match ten thousand.
You can't beat me.
Look at me.
I alone match ten thousand.
Alright, alright.
Go put on clothes.
Truly impressive.
Bring the clothes.
Aunt,
he cultivates too.
And he's very strong.
Stronger than all of you.
With a mortal post,
he's even a Primordial Immortal.
Interesting.
If you can keep up,
then follow us.
[Miasma Grove]
Miasma fills the grove;
beasts lurk around.
No sword flight allowed here.
The miasma will suppress your powers.
This trial lasts seven days.
No early departure.
Give it your all.
I'll patrol the perimeter.
If you face insurmountable danger,
crush the Message Jade.
I'll descend from the sky
to rescue you.
As for this brave warrior...
Me?
Who else?
Understood.
I will stand guard here.
Awaiting your triumph, Your Highness.
Alright.
I won't have to tie you up.
You'd have to be able to tie me up.
General Yuwen, rest assured.
I'll risk my life
to keep Xuanya safe.
You must be careful.
Miasma Grove is full
of demons and beasts.
It's extremely dangerous.
You must be cautious.
No, no, no. Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
Ahead lies the Grove's depths.
Everyone, be extremely careful.
Get your magic instruments ready.
Be careful.
Let's go.
Careful.
Isn't Miasma Grove
supposed to be dangerous?
Along the way,
let alone demons,
we haven't even seen a mosquito.
Aside from the oppressive foul aura,
it's not as perilous as Aunt said.
Everyone,
this place is safe for now.
Let's part ways for now.
Let's each seek secret treasures.
Alright.
Xuanya, be careful.
Senior, are you alright?
Are you alright?
Though no demons or beasts are here,
there's still miasma poison.
We must not let our guard down.
Xuanya,
we should go together.
That way, we can look out
for each other.
Wang Qi and I
will head north for plants.
We won't disturb you then.
Senior Changshou?
This path is far too dangerous.
It's beyond my level.
I'll take this path.
- Farewell.
- Senior.
See you outside.
In such a perilous place,
Senior Changshou goes alone,
unwilling to burden others.
His courage is truly rare.
This trial will last seven days.
No one may leave early.
When they run
into trouble they cannot handle,
they will crush the Message Jade.
Then, Jiu Jiu will descend
to rescue them.
Is that clear to all of you?
Remember.
This time, your targets are
everyone here for the trial.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tears fall, this fate's not done♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪